人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译  双语字幕
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.YYeTs.com
你被监视着
You are being watched.
■
・ 翻译  阿好
・ 翻译  紫玉
■
・ 翻译  惠子
政府有一套秘密系统
The government has a secret system--
■
・ 翻译  卫老哥
・ 翻译  王小麦
一台每时每刻都在监控你的机器
a machine that spies on you every hour of every day.
■
翻  幸田实果子
译  灰灰是菇凉
我设计这台机器是为了侦测恐怖行动
I designed the machine to detect acts of terror
■
・ 校对  阿好
但它却看到了一切
but it sees everything--
■
压制  灰灰是菇凉
牵涉普通人的暴力罪行
violent crimes involving ordinary people.
阿包  烟幕迟迟  吉吉  阿包  烟幕迟迟  吉吉  阿包  烟幕迟迟  吉吉  阿包  烟幕迟迟  吉吉
■
时间轴
政府认为这些人无关紧要
The government considered these people irrelevant.
我们不
We don't.
受当局追捕  我们只能秘密活动
Hunted by the authorities, we work in secret.
你永远找不到我们
You'll never find us.
特效
灰灰
但无论是受害人还是行凶者
But victim or perpetrator,
总监
阿好
只要你的号码被列出来  我们就会找到你
if your number's up, we'll find you.
疑犯追踪
第三季 第五集
开门
Open the door!
这是肝脏
That's a human liver.
我们得马上送去市医院  有病人等着救命呢
We have to get that to City General. A patient's life depends on it.
我们老板更等着救命
Our boss's life depends on it more.
把枪扔下
Drop the gun,
否则你朋友就要挨枪
or your friend is gonna get it.
肝脏拿好
Here's your liver.
那个  比琳达  不管你叫啥
Look, Belinda, or whatever your name is...
你刚刚救了我的命
you just saved my life.
我要如何才能
How can I ever possibly--
搞定了  芬奇
All done here, Finch.
倒不是说一定要拘于礼节  肖女士
Not to be a stickler about etiquette, Ms. Shaw,
但我认为马瑟斯先生只是想谢谢你
but I believe that Mr. Mathers was in the midst of thanking you.
你付钱雇我救他  没付钱听他废话
You paid me to save him, not listen to him talk.
虽说你的战斗水平令人赞叹
And while your combat skills are impressive,
但服务态度实在有待提高
your bedside manner still leaves a little something to be desired.
我想你过来一趟
I was thinking you might stop by,
我们可以喝杯茶讨论一下
and we could discuss it over a nice cup of tea.
听起来不错  芬奇
As fun as that sounds, Finch,
不过免了
I'll pass.
我不喜欢这样在公开场合会面  约格洛夫
I don't like meeting out in the open like this, Yogorov.
放松  西蒙斯
Relax, Simmons.
这是你给我们的地点
This place was on the map you gave us.
你看到有摄像头了吗
You see any cameras?
-铁尼是吧  -对
- So, Terney? - Yeah.
我们的合作项目进展如何了
What's the status on our joint operation?
一切就位
Everything's in place.
我们这边可以了  只等你们安排会面了
Our part's good to go. We just need you to arrange the meeting.
没问题
No problem.
我们会安排所有人到一个房间
We'll get all the players in one room.
一个极为安全的房间
One very secure room.
既然我们老大要参与
If our boss is gonna be involved,
就一定要万无一失
this has gotta be airtight.
约翰
John...
早晚有一天  我会给你一枪
one of these days, I'm just gonna shoot you.
见怪不怪了
I get that a lot.
抓获现形啊
Busted, huh?
芬奇和我早就知道你私下的计划了
Finch and I have known about your side project for a while.
据我们所知
From what we've seen,
你掌握的足够扳倒他们一半的组织了
you've got enough to bring down half the organization.
你可以拿住他们
You could bust them,
跟他们做交易供出其他人
make deals to take down the rest.
唐纳利特工用过这招了
Special Agent Donnelly tried that.
但HR又死灰复燃  因为我们没抓住头儿
But HR rebuilt itself from ashes 'cause we didn't cut off the head.
要是我们抓住了
If we had,
卡尔也许还活着
Cal might still be alive.
我现在另寻他途了
I'm playing by different rules now.
不做交易
No deals.
在没抓到老大之前我不会轻举妄动
And I won't make a move until I can bring down the boss.
他们在跟俄罗斯人合作某种项目
They're running some joint operation with the Russians.
我是我能监视他们的会面
If I can just get eyes on that meeting,
也许就能查出HR头目的真实身份
I might finally ID the head of HR.
-需要帮忙吗  -不
- Need help? - No.
不过如果我需要的话  一定第一个找你
But if I do, you'll be my first call.
芬奇  你说我们有新号码了
Finch, I thought you said we had a new number.
是的
We do,
但这号码查不到任何匹配的记录
but this one doesn't match any social security number on record.
这九位数是移民局颁发的外国人登记号码
The nine digits in question are a USCIS alien registration number.
绿卡号码
Green card number.
这是位移民
We're looking for an immigrant.
而且  珍瑞卡・芝诺娃女士来自俄罗斯索恩泽
Specifically, Ms. Genrika Zhirova of Solntsevo, Russia.
芝诺娃女士的信息很难查
Information on Ms. Zhirova is a little hard to come by.
她完全没有任何网络数据
She has virtually no digital footprint.
我目前只查到一个已知地址
All I have so far is a last known address.
在布朗克斯南区的公建楼
It's a housing project in the South Bronx.
我甚至找不到此女的照片
I can't even find a photo of the woman.
那就去亲眼看看她吧
Then let's go have a look at her.
斯通探员  海关入境处的
Agent Stone, immigration and customs.
我来找珍瑞卡・芝诺娃
I'm looking for Genrika Zhirova.
珍瑞卡
Genrika!
还没发现目标  不过我在她住处发现了毒品
No eyes on the target yet, but I see drugs at her place.
也许这就是我们来此的原因
Could have something to do with why we're here.
这区很乱
Rough neighborhood.
这女人卷进的事儿
Whatever this woman's into,
我感觉肯定没好儿
I got a feeling it's gonna get messy.
有什么事吗
Can I help you?
你是  珍瑞卡
Y-you're Genrika?
珍  没人叫我珍瑞卡
Gen. Nobody calls me Genrika.
你父母在吗
Are your parents here?
我妈在俄罗斯坐牢
My mom's in prison in Russia.
从没见过我爸
I never knew my dad.
我几年前过来跟我外公住
I came here a few years ago to live with my grandfather.
他在哪里
And where is he?
坟墓里
Cemetery.
八个月前去世的
He died eight months ago.
你们不是已经知道这些了吗
Shouldn't you guys already know this stuff?
那你现在是跟
So now you live with, um...
瓦迪姆
Vadim.
我们算是  远房亲戚吧
We're, like, third cousins or something.
他现在负责照顾我
He's supposed to be taking care of me now.
这样他就能每月领200外块  外加免费住所
Which means he gets an extra 200 a month and a free place to live.
跟她住一起  他们应该付双倍的钱
They should pay me twice that to put up with her.
成天偷偷摸摸  到处拍照
Always sneaking around, taking pictures.
疯丫头还以为自己是间谍
Crazy little girl thinks she's a spy.
我在进行职业训练
I'm just practicing for my career.
什么职业
Career doing what?
国际间谍
International espionage.
这是要查什么
What's this about?
例行检查
Just a routine check.
例行个屁
Routine, my ass.
我的移民身份有问题吗
Is there a problem with my immigration status?
-不是  我  -他们为什么派你来
- No. I-- - Why'd they send you?
一直是克罗斯探员负责我这边
Agent Cross normally handles my case.
没有克罗斯探员这人
There is no Agent Cross.
今天要付房租  否则我们要被赶出去了
那个  你这儿有什么需要帮助吗
Look, do you need any help here?
我没事  不过你害我上学迟到了
I'm fine, but you're making me late for school.
肖女士跟芝诺娃女士的谈话
Ms. Shaw's conversation with Ms. Zhirova
虽不甚和谐  倒也颇具启发性
was, if not harmonious, at least illuminating.
四年前
Four years ago,
她母亲因抗议普京当局而坐牢
her mother was in prison for protesting the Putin administration.
她外公就把珍带到这里与他同住
So her grandfather brought Gen here to live with him.
现在她只剩一个人了
Now she's all alone.
这里对孩子可不安全
Not exactly the safest place for a kid.
那远房亲戚瓦迪姆也不是个顾家的
And Cousin Vadim's no Suzy homemaker.
无论如何
Whatever's going on...
我看这丫头不可能是行凶者
I doubt this girl's the perpetrator.
应该就是她最近的生活变动
I wouldn't be surprised if the recent changes in her circumstances
导致了威胁
have something to do with the threat.
其实  肖女士  要是你能
Perhaps, Ms. Shaw, had you been
在问她是否需要帮助时更热忱一点
a touch more solicitous when asking her if she needed help...
怎么了  我问过了  她说没有
What? I asked, she said no.
要我说  这孩子能照顾好自
If you ask me, the kid can take care of her--
还好吗
Is everything all right?
你肯定不会相信  芬奇
You're not gonna believe this, Finch.
肖刚才被个十岁的孩子发现了
Shaw just got made by a ten-year-old.
什么样的小屁孩儿会用反跟踪策略
What kind of a weird-ass kid uses counter-surveillance tactics?
我来接手
I got it from here.
不过我想你有点吓到她了
But I think you freaked her out a little.
彼此彼此
It's mutual.
我去查她的住所
I'll recon her building.
里瑟先生
Mr. Reese,
我们得谈谈肖女士的事
we need to have a talk about Ms. Shaw.
别担心  我用了我们的私密线路
Don't worry, I've got us up on a private line.
你看  这样对那小姑娘的安全可没好处
Look, it won't do to save this little girl's life
肖女士把人家吓得半死
only to have her scared to death by Ms. Shaw.
也许我们最好让她离芝诺娃女士远一点儿
Perhaps it would be best if we kept her at arm's length from Ms. Zhirova.
我没意见  我讨厌小孩子
Fine with me, I hate kids.
肖女士
Ms. Shaw?
怎么  芬奇
What, Finch?
你以为我没监听你的办公室
You think I didn't bug your office?
我们有麻烦了  芬奇
We've got trouble, Finch.
抓住她
Get her!
别看这丫头年龄小  芬奇  她麻烦可是够大
Whoever this girl is, Finch, she has a very grown-up problem.
走吧
Come on.
存档音频
911报警电话
911 emergency.
我刚目击了一起事故
I just saw an accident.
车胎爆了  车子失去了控制
A tire blew, and the driver lost control.
请派人来
Please send someone.
车上的急救设备拿来
I need an ETA on that bus!
准备个固定支架  可能会需要
And get a back brace ready, just in case!
顶完全塌了
The top's completely collapsed.
我试试救司机
I'll try to get to the driver.
司机已经死亡
Driver's DOA.
喂
Hello?
有生还者
I've got a 10-45.
这里有人还活着
Someone's alive in there.
我看不到人
I can't see 'em.
我去看另一边
I'll check the other side.
喂  你受伤了吗
Hey, there. Are you hurt?
应该没有
I don't think so.
我爸还好吗
Is my dad okay?
你叫什么名字  宝贝
What's your name, sweetheart?
萨姆恩
Sameen.
好的萨姆恩  坚持住孩子
Okay, Sameen, hang on, kiddo.
我这就来了  好吗
I'm coming to you, okay?
芬奇  不是说让我离这孩子远点儿吗
Finch, so much for keeping me away from the kid.
-芝诺娃女士  还安全吗  -目前是
- Ms. Zhirova. Is she safe? - For now.
不过我看敌人是不会放弃的
But I don't think our tangos have given up.
我也一样
Me either.
你在哪里
What's your 20?
下层地下室  下边几层
Sub-basement. A few floors down.
守在那里
Hold your position.
我这就过去
I'm on my way.
知道这是怎么回事吗
Any idea what this is about?
知道那些是什么人  为什么要逮你吗
Do you know who those men were or why they tried to grab you?
也许因为我是间谍
Probably because I'm a spy.
她不知道
She doesn't know.
那我们是完全不知道谁想抓她了
So we have no idea who's after her?
发号施令的那个人手在颤抖
The guy giving orders had a tremor in his hand.
可能是帕金森症
Could be Parkinson's.
这倒不多见  也许有助于查清他的身份
It's a rare enough condition. It might help us to identify him.
好吧  约翰  我在东北角跟你碰头
All right, John, I'll meet you at the northeast corner.
不  待着别动  肖女士  里瑟先生会去找你
No. Please stay put, Ms. Shaw. Mr. Reese will come to you.
你的任务是全力保护芝诺娃女士
Your job is to protect Ms. Zhirova at all costs.
遵命  长官
Sir, yes, sir.
我以为你是机器人
I thought you might be a robot.
数据库里没查到那帕金森的资料
No hits for Parkinson's in the database,
但如果你想找坏人  那可来对地方了
but if you're looking for bad guys, you've gone to the right place.
那小姑娘是住在个"冲击区"里
Your girl lives in an impact zone.
听起来不怎么妙
That doesn't sound good.
她那里是个盲区
Her address is in a blind spot
没有资金覆盖监控
where funding for domain awareness ran out.
罪犯最喜欢去没有监控的地方
Criminals like to go where the cameras aren't.
没有看到那位西装男
No sign of our friend in the suit.
但她又在打她的秘密电话
But she's on another one of her secret calls.
肯定在谋划什么
Definitely up to something.
去查清楚
Find out what.
挂了
Gotta go.
卡特  昨晚你在哪儿
Carter, where were you last night?
我们一群人去喝酒了  我还给你留言了
A bunch of us went out for drinks. I left you a message.
新枪啊  拉斯基
New gun, Laskey?
喜欢吗  我上周末刚买的
Like it? I just bought it last weekend.
新泽西枪械展
Gun show in Jersey.
那你是带着它非法跨越州界了
So you brought it across state lines illegally?
你知道纽约的所有枪支
You do know that every gun in New York
都必须进行弹道测试存档  是吧
has to have a ballistics test on file, right?
挺好
Nice.
你们抓到那丫头了吗
You guys have the girl yet?
快了  但她有人帮忙
We're closing in, but she has help.
-你叫什么名字  -不重要
- What's your name? - Not important.
那你是谁
Who are you?
为什么在这儿
Why are you here?
你怎么知道我会有麻烦
How'd you know I was gonna be in trouble?
怎么样了  约翰
How's it going, John?
还在清理营救路线
Still clearing our extraction route,
跟两分钟之前一样
same as I was two minutes ago.
约翰是谁
Who's John?
是你朋友吗
Is he your friend?
-是你男朋友吗  -不是
- Is he your boyfriend? - No.
是同事
He's a coworker.
"同事"  那这就是你的工作了
"Coworker." So this is your job?
你是什么人  特种部队之类的吗
What are you? Like, Spec Ops or something?
天啊  你在什么机构工作
Oh, man! What agency do you work for?
中情局  国安局  情报与安全司令部
CIA? NSA? INSCOM?
那种大机构为什么会关心我的事
Why would a big agency like that care what happens to me?
我们不是大机构
We're not a big agency.
那小机构为什么会关心我的事
Why would a small agency care what happens to me?
我们不是什么机构
We're not any agency.
我们只是
We're just a...
我也不知道我们是什么
I don't even know what we are.
说实话  我加入就是为了那条狗
To be honest, I'm only in it for the dog.
你们还有条狗
You guys have a dog?
没有看到他们
No sign of 'em here.
安全  检查下一个房间
Clear. Check the next room.
我看到两个敌人  芬奇
I got eyes on two tangos, Finch.
我去把他们放倒
I'm taking 'em out.
绝对不行
Absolutely not!
要是你出了什么事  芝诺娃女士无力自保
If anything happened to you, Ms. Zhirova would be defenseless.
让里瑟先生负责绑架者
Let Mr. Reese worry about the kidnappers.
你负责把那小姑娘带出去  快
You just get the girl out of there. Now.
我们能搞定  好的
We can handle it. All right.
来吧
Come on.
-他们在那儿  -跑
- There they are! - Run!
快追
Let's move!
这边
This way.
没事的  我总来这里
It's okay. I'm in here all the time.
我的监听站
My listening station.
我们在这儿很安全
We should be safe here.
都是你做的吗
You did all this?
跟你说了我是间谍
Told you I was a spy.
但这不是我做的
But I didn't do this.
芬奇
Finch.
我想我知道这是怎么回事了
I think I might know what this is all about.
珍监听了楼里的所有电话
Gen has this whole building wired,
看来有人发现了她在干的事情
and it looks like someone found out what she was up to.
知道是谁吗
Any idea who?
有没有你录过什么人
Did any of the people you ever recorded
提到过犯罪的事情
talk about committing any crimes?
很多
Lots of them.
我监听所有可疑的人
I bugged anyone who looked suspicious.
你就没想过
Did it ever occur to you
这主意馊得不得了
that that might have been a really bad idea?
我是想把那些毒贩
I was just trying to get the drug dealers
从楼里赶出去
out of my building.
你把磁带给过任何人吗
Did you give the tapes to anyone?
还没有
Not yet.
纽约跟俄罗斯一样  不能相信警察
New York's just like Russia-- you can't trust the cops.
我想等录到毒贩的铁证
I was waiting till I had something on the dealers
让他们无法忽视
that was too big to ignore.
是啊  他们可没忽视你  孩子
Yeah, they're not ignoring you, kid.
我现在知道了
I know that now.
那么磁带在哪儿呢
So where are the tapes?
安全的地方
Somewhere safe.
我也是间谍  记得吗
I'm a spy too, remember?
知道磁带的位置了  芬奇
Got a location on the tapes, Finch.
你记下来吧
You're gonna wanna write this down.
安全
Clear.
他们躲在管道里  不过我有办法
We got rats in the walls, but I got a plan.
把后备箱的面罩拿进来
Get the masks from the trunk.
走
Let's go!
你还好吗
You all right?
我没事
I'm fine.
我叫肖
I'm Shaw.
很高兴认识你
Nice to meet you.
你从哪儿学到这一套的
Where'd you learn how to do that?
我外公教我的
My grandfather taught me.
他当过克格勃
He was in the KGB.
给了我这个
Gave me this too.
列宁勋章
Order of Lenin.
我总是随身带着
I wear it everywhere I go.
你应该卖掉  应该值不少钱
You should sell it. Probably worth a lot of money.
你怎么回事
What's wrong with you?
你为什么
I mean, why are you...
会这样
like this?
刚才让你畏缩的那种情绪
You know that thing that made you flinch?
我感受不到
I don't get that.
你感受不到害怕
You don't get scared?
还有悲伤
Or sad.
还有开心  还有孤独
Or happy or lonely.
我会生气没错  但是
I do angry okay, but...
也就这样了
that's about it.
发生过什么事吗
Did something happen?
从我记事起就这样了
Been this way as long as I can remember.
我是
I was...
跟你差不多大的时候
about your age...
发现我跟别人不一样
when I figured out I was different.
那是什么
What's that?
氟利昂
R-22.
他们肯定是打破了大楼的空调管
They must have punctured the pipes for the building's AC.
我们十秒之内就会头晕
We'll be dizzy in 10 seconds,
四十秒之内会昏迷
unconscious in 40.
之后呢
What happens after that?
你不会想知道的  走
You don't wanna know. Come on.
跟我说话  萨姆恩  你喜欢看电视吗
So talk to me, Sameen. You like TV?
你最喜欢看什么节目
What's your favorite show?
没有最喜欢的
I don't have one.
每个地方的节目都不一样
They're different everywhere you go.
你经常搬家吗
You move around a lot?
是的
Yeah.
我爸爸是军人
My dad's in the military.
他喜欢看电视
He likes TV.
我们会一起看橄榄球
We watch football together.
你跟他一样是勇敢的战士
You're being a trooper just like him.
我们会打电话给你妈妈  好吗
We're gonna call your mom, okay?
她会过来  好好照顾你
And she's gonna come and take care of you.
准备好出来了吗
Ready to get outta here?
抓到那孩子了  清理掉大人
We got the kid. Take out the trash.
下次记得清理好后备箱  白痴
Maybe clean out your trunk next time, dumbass.
找到她了吗
Do you have her?
没有  我们正希望你找到了呢
No, we were hoping that you had.
不过很高兴你还活着
But I'm glad to know you're still alive.
就你高兴
That makes one of us.
知道他们抓她去哪儿了吗
Any clue where they took her?
正在查
We're working on it.
小熊只能追踪芝诺娃女士
Bear could only track MS. Zhirova--
珍  她叫珍
Gen. Her name is Gen.
他只能追踪珍到街上
He could only track Gen as far as the street.
她现在可能在城里任何地方
She could be anywhere in the city by now.
绑我的那人  开不了口了
The guy who kidnapped me... isn't talking.
不过  我拿到他的手机了
But, I got his cell.
也许能查到那个颤抖的人
It might lead us to the guy with the tremor.
把他的位置给我
Give me his location.
剩下的交给我
I'll handle the rest.
小熊发现血迹了  肖  很多
Bear found blood, Shaw. A lot of it.
他似乎认为是你的
And he seems to think it's yours.
我没事
I'm fine.
我发给你一个地址  那医生欠我们人情
I'm sending you the address of a doctor who owes us a favor.
约翰可以去找那个颤抖的人
John can track the man with the tremors.
我想我有办法查出
And I think I finally have the means
为什么会有人要绑架她了
to determine why she was abducted.
我在珍说的位置找到了那些磁带
I've recovered Gen's tapes right where she said they were.
小姑娘甚合我意
A girl after my own heart.
我知道这次失手了  芬奇
I know this went sideways, Finch.
但不能我一犯错你就罚我做冷板凳
But you can't bench me for every mistake.
我不是为错误惩罚你
I'm not punishing you for an error.
我是在保护你  你受伤了
I'm protecting you because you're hurt.
你做得够多了  肖女士
You've done enough, Ms. Shaw.
下面的事我们来
We'll take it from here.
第1季第11集中被宅总用钱砸着救里叔的伊拉克名医  P.S. 此号码可打通
法鲁克・马达尼医生
纽约市东99街2510号
我们来这干什么
What are we doing here?
偏离我们的巡逻线路了
This is way off our beat.
吃午饭  不谢
Lunch. You're welcome.
不是吧  你真要为个墨西哥卷饼排这么长队
Come on. Do you really wanna wait in that line for a taco?
不  我要你去排队买两个
No, I want you to wait for two tacos,
多加份烤肉和泡菜沙拉
extra bulgogi, and some kimchi slaw.
你想吃什么随便
Plus whatever you want.
追踪手机
雷蒙德・铁尼
有问题马上给我电话  明白吗
Any problems, you call me. We clear?
合作项目一如计划
Joint operation's on schedule.
很好  货已经送出
Good. The package has been delivered.
复制电话
雷蒙德・铁尼
通话中
西蒙斯
付钱给他
Pay the man.
我有点事
Look, something came up.
把车开走  替我打下掩护
Take the car and cover for me.
我会自己回辖区
I'll make my way back to the precinct.
没胃口了
Lost my appetite.
不行  伙计  该你订披萨了
No, man. It's your turn to call for pizza, man.
我才不要打
I don't wanna call--
恶心
看标签啊  哈罗德
Read the labels, Harold.
肖女士  你还好吗
Ms. Shaw, everything all right?
发现谁绑了珍吗
Do you know who took Gen?
还没
Not yet.
不过我注意到
But I can't help noticing
你根本没去我推荐的医生那里
that you are nowhere near the doctor that I recommended.
事实上  你似乎是
In fact, you seem to be...
要告诉我为什么你手里的货
You wanna tell me why you're holding the same junk
和绑了珍的人一样吗
as the guys who took Gen?
坐下  瓦迪姆
Sit down, Vadim.
给你带了点东西
Got a little something for you.
不错吧
Good, huh?
要是浪费了就太可惜了
It'd be a shame to see it all go to waste.
可以让你吸嗨了
Now I can either re-up your stash,
也可以全冲掉
or I can flush it all.
熊孩子
Stupid kid.
监听人家的屋子
Bugging people's rooms.
他们扫描到了发射器
They sweep for transmitters.
如今谁还用接线的
Who uses wires anymore?
他们找到线  就找到了录音机
But they find the wire, then they find recorders,
就找到了我
then they find me.
你跟他们说了珍的事
You told them about Gen?
他们已经知道了  他们给了我这个
They knew already. They give me this.
他们让我找到磁带
They tell me to find the tapes
她失踪了也不要上报
and not to report it if she went missing.
谁
Who?
俄黑手党
Bratva.
俄罗斯人
The--the Russians.
不知道你有没有意识到  但你要求的太多了
I don't know if you realize, but you're asking a lot.
不知道你有没有意识到  这不是请求
I don't know if you realize, but I'm not asking.
追踪手机
芬奇  我离绑架者的手机很近了
Finch, I'm closing in on the kidnapper's cell.
不知道你有没有意识到  这不是请求
I don't know if you realize, but I'm not asking.
意外通常不需要用到铲子
Most accidents don't require a shovel.
那是我在查的人
That's my guy.
付钱给我在查的人
Paying my guy.
芬奇  我知道谁绑了那小姑娘
Finch, I know who has the girl.
我也知道了  里瑟先生
So do I, Mr. Reese.
没人告诉你监听别人很不礼貌吗
Didn't anyone ever tell you it's not polite to spy on people,
小姑娘
little girl?
那些磁带在哪儿
Now... where are the tapes?
我们打电话给你妈妈了  好吗  萨姆恩
So we called your mom, okay, Sameen?
她正在赶过来
She's coming right now.
我爸呢  他是不是也困在车里了
Where's my dad? Is he stuck in the car too?
宝贝  那车祸很严重
Sweetheart, it was a really bad accident.
你爸爸受伤了
Your dad got hurt.
那你为什么在这陪我
Then why are you with me?
你应该去照顾他
You should be taking care of him.
是啊  我也希望  宝贝
Yeah, I wish I could, sweetie.
但有时候人受伤太重
But sometimes people get hurt so bad
就会睡过去
that they fall asleep,
醒不过来了
and they don't wake up.
你是说他死了吗
You mean he's dead?
我很遗憾  萨姆恩
Look, I'm so sorry, Sameen.
要是有什么我能做的
If there was anything I could have done...
我饿了  能给我个三明治吗
I'm hungry. Can I have a sandwich?
肖女士  你还没去看医生
Ms. Shaw, you're still not at the doctor.
我强烈要求你去
I must insist that you...
芬奇  卡特发现HR怎么找到珍了
Finch, Carter knows how HR found Gen.
他们查了她的指纹
They ran her fingerprints.
所有合法移民在入境时
Every legal immigrant gets fingerprinted
都会留下指纹记录
when they enter the country.
但还是不知道她抓到HR什么把柄
That still doesn't explain exactly what she has on HR.
那个颤抖的家伙如何
How's our friend with the tremor?
醒着  但是不怎么开口
Awake, but not exactly a chatterbox.
也许我们应该让约格洛夫先生
Perhaps we should let Mr. Yogorov
和警探西蒙斯来说
and Detective Simmons do the talking.
什么样的合作项目
What kind of joint operation?
互利互惠的
One in our mutual interest.
我们老大想要你们的人停销老产品
My boss wants your people to stop moving the old product
搞点新玩意
and try something new.
他们说过是什么产品吗
They ever say what the product is?
没有  不过你拍的一张照片
No, but one of your pictures
可能抵过千言万语了
may turn out to be worth a thousand words.
你发现的油罐车
The tanker that you spotted
边上有个化学式
bears a chemical formula on the side.
KMnO4
KMnO4.
高锰酸钾
Potassium permanganate.
通常用于水处理
Commonly used in water treatment,
但也可以用做关键原料制成一种危险的新型毒品
But also a key ingredient in a dangerous new class of drugs:
合成卡西酮
Synthetic Cathinones.
俗称"浴盐"
Otherwise known as Bath Salts.
说到底  HR在贩毒
So basically, HR's dealing drugs.
可能不只是贩毒
Perhaps not simply dealing.
毒品虽能让人兴奋
The drug may be intoxicating,
但纯高锰酸钾是有毒的
but pure potassium permanganate is just toxic.
接触会产生类似帕金森症的症状
Exposure produces symptoms similar to Parkinson's.
那位朋友不是病了
Our new friend isn't sick.
他是HR的制毒师
He's been cooking designer drugs for HR.
谢了  芬奇
Thank you, Finch.
硝酸甘油
Nitroglycerin.
非常不稳定
It's highly unstable.
轻微震动  就可能引爆
The slightest shock could set it off.
弄倒了  你的膝盖就会被炸飞
Drop it, and it'll blow your knees off.
换我肯定拼命稳住
I'd hold steady if I were you.
你一直在为HR制毒
So you've been making drugs for HR.
俄罗斯人负责什么
Where do the Russians come in?
HR制毒  俄罗斯人贩运
HR makes the stuff, the Russians move it.
他们安排了一个会面
They called in a big meeting.
跟HR的老大吗
With the head of HR?
城里所有的毒枭
The top dealers in town.
HR要俄罗斯人下令
HR wants the Russians to lay down the law,
逼他们停售可卡因  海洛因之类的
force 'em to stop selling Coke, "H", whatever,
转而卖"浴盐"
start selling Salts.
听到了吗  芬奇
You get all that, Finch?
是的  我在珍的一盘磁带里发现的内容
Yes, and I've found something in one of Gen's recordings
能证实此事
that confirms it.
哥伦比亚可以滚蛋了
Screw the Columbians.
这玩意儿直接美国本土制造
This stuff is made right here in the U.S. of A.
我们有大量设备
All right, we've got a massive facility.
城里大卖  我们全发达
City gets hooked, we all get rich.
制毒窝点在哪
So where's the cook site?
我只参与了第一批的制作
I only helped with the first batch,
但有个管子爆裂了
but a pipe burst.
我被浇了一身  变成了这样
I got hosed with whatever did this to me.
之后  他们搬去了更大的地方
After that, they moved-- someplace bigger.
求你了  我就知道这么多
Please. That's all I know.
我相信你
And I believe you.
你们不能把我丢在这儿
You can't just leave me here!
HR为满足己欲  恣意操控本市的犯罪
So HR is tailoring crime in the city to fit their needs,
那些磁带可以呈缉毒局为证
and we've got the tapes to prove it to the DEA.
卡特  我知道你说过不做交易
Look, Carter, I know you said no deals.
我们当然要拿磁带来换那小姑娘
Of course we trade the tapes for the girl.
我们真要把他就丢在这儿吗
Are we really gonna leave him like that?
放松  那只是玉米糖浆
Relax. It's just corn syrup.
我们接到911电话报警  有人心脏病发吗
We got a 911 call. Someone's having a heart attack?
抱歉  我们必须检查
Sorry, we're required to check.
只要让我们进去
If you'd just let us in...
外面的救护车是怎么回事
What was that ambulance doing out front?
小姑娘在哪儿
Where's the girl?
那是HR的事儿
That's HR's deal.
警察可能会杀了那孩子
The cops might kill a kid.
我手下是有原则的
My people have standards.
知道他们在哪儿做的吗
You know where they make this stuff?
我只负责分销
I just handle distribution.
-试过吗  -当然没有
- Ever try it? - Hell no.
我的身体很干净
My body's a temple.
最近的六个月出过国吗
Have you left the country in the last six months?
没有
No.
有过不安全性行为吗
Ever had unprotected sex?
干嘛  你要提供吗
Why? You offering?
没有
No.
患过肝炎  疟疾  锥虫病或巴贝西虫病吗
Ever had hepatitis, malaria, chagas disease, or babesiosis?
没有  你问这些干嘛
No. What the hell is this about?
我需要血
I need blood.
要用你的
So I'm taking yours.
你连我的血型都不知道
You don't even know my blood type.
我是AB阳型  全适受血者
I'm AB Positive. Universal recipient.
让HR的人接电话
Get HR on the phone.
有人想跟你说话
Someone wants to talk with you.
叫那小姑娘接电话
Put the girl on the phone,
否则让约格洛夫脑袋开花
or I paint the walls with Yogorov's brains.
肖  是你吗
Shaw, is that you?
撑住  孩子  我来救你了
Hang on, kiddo. I'm coming for you.
好了
Okay.
我们来谈谈条件吧
Let's talk terms.
我在拷贝HR的磁带了
I'm copying the HR tapes.
但还有数小时的音频
But I have hours of analog audio
没法加快拷贝速度
and no way to speed up the process.
珍等不了数小时  芬奇
Gen doesn't have hours, Finch.
我们得告诉HR同意拿磁带换回
We need to tell HR we're willing to trade the tapes for--
我早想到了  约翰
Way ahead of you, John.
你雇我是为了救珍  不是为了抓腐败警察
You hired me to save Gen, not bust dirty cops.
所以除非你有更好的主意  哈罗德
So unless you got a better idea, Harold,
否则磁带给我
I'm gonna need those tapes.
我们有麻烦了  卡特
We got a problem, Carter.
肖把磁带拿走了
Shaw took the tapes.
她正要去兰德尔岛跟西蒙斯会面
She's meeting Simmons on Randall's Island
拿磁带换小姑娘
to trade them for the girl.
我会过去补救
But I'll be there to change the odds.
需要帮忙吗
Need help?
如果我需要的话  一定第一个找你
If I do, you'll be my first call.
我正在监视卡特
I got eyes on her.
她那西装男的朋友知道会面的事
Her pal in the suit knows about the meet.
你走进埋伏了
You're walking into an ambush.
不  他才是
No, he is.
你们跟我来
You guys are with me.
卡特  你在这儿  听着
Carter, there you are. Look.
我有点事要找你谈谈
I need to talk to you about something.
我们明天可以谈一整天
Yeah, we can talk all day tomorrow.
拜托  卡特
Come on, Carter.
我之前帮你在队长那里打掩护了
I covered for you with the sarge.
现在我需要你指点
And I need your advice.
我遇到了麻烦
I'm having a problem.
工作上跟人起冲突了
With somebody on the job.
好吧  什么麻烦
All right, what is it?
不能在这儿说
Not here.
我知道附近有个酒吧
I know a bar nearby.
好了  我们要拿下磁带
All right, we're about to get the tapes
还有那个西装男
and the man in the suit.
好戏开始了  各位
Showtime, people.
等我命令开火
Prepare to fire on my order.
收到回答
Acknowledge.
收到回答  一号
Acknowledge, one.
收到回答  二号
Acknowledge, two.
人都去哪儿了
Where is everybody?
警官
Officer...
我想报告一起绑架案
I'd like to report a kidnapping.
你赢了
You win.
带她走吧
Take her.
小姑娘不在这儿
The girl's not here.
磁带也不在
Neither are the tapes.
看来你的情报不准啊
Looks like you got bad intel.
也不是一无所获
Not a total loss.
我们是时候聊两句了
It's about time you and I had a little talk.
得给你赞一个  芬奇
Gotta hand it to you, Finch.
这确实是更好的主意
This was a better idea.
卡特说过铁尼警探参与了合作项目
Carter said Detective Terney was involved in the joint operation,
据此推断  他的GPS信号
so it seemed reasonable to assume that his GPS signal
能把我们带到制毒室
might lead us to the lab.
就告诉我往哪儿走
Just tell me which way to go.
右/对
Right.
但愿
I hope.
我们的人成百上千
There are hundreds of us, you know.
你真认为你能赢吗
You really think you can win?
聚沙成塔  一次一个
Armies fall...one soldier at a time.
准备离开了吗
You ready to get out of here?
芬奇
Finch,
你懂多少化学
How much you know about chemistry?
足够
Enough.
两杯啤酒  杰瑞
Two beers, Jerry.
算我账上
On me.
最近如何  杰
How you doing, Jer?
不过来吗
You gonna join me?
到底什么麻烦  拉斯基
So what's the problem, Laskey?
首先
For starters,
我搭档不愿意跟我喝一杯
my own partner won't even have a drink with me.
你说工作上跟人起冲突了
So you're having a problem with someone at work.
跟谁
Who?
你
You.
到底怎么回事
I mean, what's going on?
我应该挺你
I'm supposed to have your back,
但你什么都不跟我说  我怎么帮你
but how can I help you if you don't even talk to me?
-我没事  -没事个屁
- I'm fine. - Like hell you are.
半夜神秘电话
With the secret phone calls in the night,
值班半路溜出
ducking out in the middle of a shift,
偷偷摸摸去见个西装男
hush-hush meetings with some man in a suit.
他到底是谁啊
Who is he, anyway?
我想他可不是你男朋友
'Cause I don't think he's your boyfriend.
你干嘛这么好奇
Why are you so curious?
是因为  这个吗
Is it maybe because of this?
我知道  拉斯基
I know, Laskey.
从你坐上车的那一刻我就知道
I've known from the second your ass landed in my car.
你知道那是什么感觉吗
Do you have any idea what it's like?
什么意思
What what's like?
整天巡逻
Riding around all day
都跟着个不知进退的傲慢贱人
with an arrogant bitch who doesn't know her place.
他们放你一条生路
They spared your life,
但你非要一意孤行
but you keep pushing.
现在你那位西装男要付出代价了
And now your pal in the suit is gonna pay the price.
相信我  他可用不着你担心
Trust me, he is not the one you should be worried about.
你刚帮我们耍了西蒙斯
See, you just played Simmons for us.
我们给了你假情报
We fed you bad info,
把西蒙斯和他手下从那小姑娘身边调开了
and you got Simmons and his men away from the girl.
当他们  把我指派给你时
You know, when they, uh, assigned me to you,
叫我假扮成愚蠢的菜鸟
they told me to play the dumb rookie,
看看能发现什么
see what I could find out.
但西蒙斯允许我
But Simmons gave me the authority
随时可以除掉你
to pull your card anytime I want.
你觉得呢  杰里
What ya think, Jerry?
我该给自己找个新搭档吗
Should I earn myself a new partner?
你连自己是谁都没搞清楚  小子
You don't even know who you are yet, son.
是吧
Do you?
不过  你想耍横装牛逼
But you wanna play Billy badass?
你请便
You go right ahead.
但我和你相处够久了  我知道你怕我
But I spent enough time with you to know you're afraid of me.
所以才找了个白痴朋友当支援
That's why you have your idiot friend here for backup.
我了解你  拉斯基
I know you, Laskey.
就像我了解那位杰里是布朗克斯分局风化组的警督
Just like I know Jerry back there is a lieutenant in Bronx VICE
靠敲诈妓女的钱开了这家酒吧
who paid for this bar with dirty cash from shaking down hookers.
我有证据能让他为此蹲大牢
And I have the proof to put him away for it.
我本打算等等  把你俩和其他人一起逮捕
Now I was gonna wait and arrest you two with everyone else.
但如果你想这么玩  小家伙
But if this is how you wanna play it, little man,
我只好现在就把你拿下
Guess I'll have to take you down right now.
你俩可以选敬酒  也可以选罚酒
You both can go easy... or it can be hard.
他们早该杀了你  你个贱
They should've killed you, you stupid bit--
放下枪
Put the gun down.
放下
Put it down!
坐下
Sit down.
现在我们得想法解决了
Now we gotta figure this out.
解决  你刚杀了他
Figure this out? You just killed him.
不
No.
是你杀的
You did.
这把枪在新泽西州注册在你的名下
Registered to you in the state of New Jersey.
我只需要上交做个弹道测试
All I gotta do is submit it for ballistics.
不过我不会那么做
But I'm not gonna do that.
暂时不会
Not yet.
你不再为HR工作了  小子
You don't work for HR anymore, son.
你现在为我工作
You work for me now.
从没见过这样的
Never seen anything like it.
我把消息告诉了她  她也懂了  但是
I told her the news, and she understood, but...
我不知道
I don't know.
我觉得那孩子有点问题
I think there's something wrong with the kid.
要是我不喜欢呢
What if I don't like it?
你跟瓦迪姆都住得了  哪里都能住得了
You lived with Vadim, you can live anywhere.
而且这应该是全世界最顶级的学校了
And it's supposed to be one of the top schools in the world.
不是所有孩子都能
Not every kid gets to become
有个隐型富豪当监护人
the ward of a reclusive billionaire.
你要再有麻烦
Now if you're ever in trouble again,
打这个号码
call this number.
别卖掉  好吗
Don't sell it, okay?
我知道这对你没有意义
I know it won't mean much to you,
但你拿着这个对我意义重大
but it'll mean a lot to me that you have it.
我对这种事没有感觉  孩子
I'm just not wired for this kind of stuff, kid.
我知道
I know.
我懂你了
I figured you out.
你不是没有感觉
It's not that you don't have feelings.
你就像是
It's just like...
音量调低了
the volume is turned way down.
就好像旧磁带一样
Like the sound on an old tape.
声音还在
The voices are there.
只需要去倾听
You just have to listen.
再见了  肖
Bye, Shaw.
你弄疼我了
You're hurting me.
我  违背了一些
So I... disobeyed some...
差不多是全部
pretty much all...
命令
of your orders.
我被解雇了吗
Am I fired?
正相反  肖女士
On the contrary, Ms. Shaw.
我想你终于得到这份工作了
I think you finally got the job.
关于我图书馆的监听器
Now about that bug in my library...
你还没找到  是吧
Haven't found it yet, have you?
你想我了吗
Did you miss me?
模拟互动界面激活
我们在一起会很好玩的
We're gonna have so much fun together.